all right I think that's be an exciting
我认为这是一个
video in this video you see how to
令人激动的视频 这个视频中
implement gradient descent for your
你将知道如何为含有一个隐含层的
neural network with one hidden layer in
神经网络实现梯度下降
this video I'm going to just give you
这个视频中 我将给出
the equations you need to implement in
一些公式 你需要使用这些公式
order to get back propagation on to get the
实现反向传播 来使梯度下降可以
gradient descent working and then in the
正常工作
video after this one I'll give some more
在下一个视频中
intuition about why these particular
我会解释为什么这些
equations are the accurate equations or
用来计算神经网络的
the correct equations for computing the
梯度的公式是正确的
gradients you need for your neural network
so your neural network with a single
你的神经网络现在有一个
hidden layer for now we've have
隐含层 这个网络中
parameters w1 b1 w2 and b2 and so as
有参数w1 b2 w2 和b2
a reminder if you have Nx alternative
提醒一下 让Nx等于
the um n0 input features and n1 hidden
n0个输入特征
units and n2 output units in our
n1个隐含单元 n2个输出单元
example so far we've n2 equals 1
在我们的例子中 n2=1
then the matrix W1 will be n1 by n0
矩阵W1是(n1,n0)维的
b1 will be an n1 dimensional vector so
b1是一个n1维的向量
you can write down as a n1 by 1
你可以写为(n1,1)维的矩阵
dimensional matrix really a column
而实际上是一个列向量
vector the dimensions of W2 will be n2
w2是一个(n2,n1)维的矩阵
by n1 and the dimension of b2 will be
n2 by 1 right where again so far we've
b2的维度是(n2,1)
only seen examples where n2 is equal to
再说一次 目前我们的例子
1 where you have just one a single
n2等于1 就是说你仅有一个
hidden unit so you also have a cost
隐藏层单元
function for a neural network and for
你还有一个代价函数
now I'm just going to assume that you're
现在 我假设你
doing binary classification so in that
仅做二分类
case the cost of your parameters as
这种情况下
follows is going to be 1 over m of the
参数的代价会是
average of that loss function and so L
损失函数的平均值
here is the loss when your neural network
这里的L是神经网络的损失
predicts y hat right this is really a[2]
神经网络预测的结果y^ 实际上就是a[2]
when the ground truth label is equal to y
真实的标签是y
and if you're doing binary
如果你在做二分类
classification the loss function can be
可以用之前
exactly what you use for logistic
用来做logistic回归时使用的
earlier so to train the parameters your
损失函数 就是说这个算法使用梯度下降
algorithms you need to perform gradient
来训练神经网络的参数
descent when training a neural network
在训练神经网络的时候
is important to initialize the
将参数随机初始化为
parameters randomly rounded into all zeros
0附近的值是非常重要的
we'll see later why that's the case but
我们稍后会看到为什么它很重要
after initializing the parameter to
但是在初始化参数之后
something each loop of gradient descent
每一轮的梯度下降
would compute the predictions
首先计算出预测结果
so you basically compute you know y hat(i)
很简单 计算y^(i)
for i equals 1 through m say and then
i从1到m
you need to compute the derivative so
接下来计算导数
you need to compute dw1 and that's we
你需要计算dw[1]
see the derivative of the cost function
这是代价函数对
with respect to the parameter W1 you
参数w1的导数
need to compute another variable which
你还需要计算出
is going to call db1 which is the
另一个变量db1
derivative or the slope of your cost
db1是你的代价函数对
function with respect to the variable b1
变量b1的导数
and so on similarly for the other
对于参数w2和b2
parameters w2 and b2 and then finally
也类似
the gradient descent update would be to
最后 梯度下降更新参数的公式是
update W1 as W1 minus alpha the
W1 = W1-alpha*dw1
learning rate times d w1 b1 gets
alpha是学习率
updated as b1 minus the learning rate
b1被更新为b1-学习率*db1
times db1 as similarly for w2 and b2
w2和b2类似
and sometimes I use colon equals and
有时我使用：=
sometimes equals as either either the
有时我用=
notation works fine and so this would be
俩符号差不多
one iteration of gradient descent and
这就是梯度下降迭代一次的过程
then your repeat this some number of
你重复这个过程许多次
times until your parameters look like
直到你的参数看起来
they're converging so in previous videos
收敛了 在之前的视频中
we talked about how to compute the
我们谈到了如何计算
predictions how to compute the outputs
预测结果 如何计算输出
and we saw how to do that in a
我们还知道如何用
vectorized way as well so the key is to
向量化的方式实现这些计算
know how to compute these partial
现在的重点是如何计算这些
derivative terms the dw1 db1 as well
偏导数项dw1 db1
as the derivatives dw2 and db2 so what
还有dw2 db2
I'd like to do is just give you the
我现在给出公式
equations you need in order to compute
你需要使用这些公式计算出
these derivatives and I'll defer to the
这些导数
next video which is an optional video to
我会在下一个视频中
go great turn to defer about how we came
介绍这些公式是如何被提出的
up with those formulas
下一个视频是可选视频
so then just summarize again the
我们再总结一下
equations for forword propagation so you
前向传播的公式
have z[1] equals w[1]X plus b[1] and then
z[1]=w[1]x+b[1]
a[1] equals the activation function in
a[1]等于你在这一层使用的激活函数
that layer applied elementwise z1
作用在每一个z[1]的元素上
and then z[2] equals w[2] a[1] plus b[2]
z[2]=w[2]a[1]+b[2]
and then finally this is just
这是对整个训练集
vectorize across your training set right
向量化的操作
a2 is equal to G[2] of V[2] looking for
a2 = g[2](v[2])
now if we assume you're doing binary
现在 我假设你在做二分类
classification then this activation
那么这个激活函数
function really should be the sigmoid
应该是sigmoid函数
function so I'm just throw that in here
我把他写在这里
so that's the forward propagation or the
这就是神经网络的前向传播
left-to-right forward computation for
或者说从左向右的前向计算
your neural network next let's compute
接下来 我们计算
the derivatives so this is the back
导数 这是反向传播的过程
propagation step then it computes dz2
下面计算
equals a2 minus the ground truth Y and
dZ[2]=A[2]-Y
just just as a reminder all this is
提醒一下 这是对所有样本
vectorize across example so the matrix Y
向量化操作 这个矩阵Y
is this um 1 by m matrix that lists all
是一个1*m的矩阵
of your m examples horizontally then it
你所有的m个样本横向的列在这里
turns out dw2 is equal to this in fact
dw[2]等于这个
um these first three equations are very
事实上 这三个等式
similar to gradient descent for logistic regression
和logistic回归的梯度下降非常类似
comma axis is equals 1 comma um keepdims equals True
,axis=1,keepdims=True
and just a little detail this NP
一点细节
dot sum is a Python numpy commands for
这个np.sum是Python numpy的指令
summing across one dimension of a
用来对矩阵的某一个维度求和
matrix in this case summing horizontally
这个例子中 横向求和
and what keepdims does is it prevents
keepdims的作用是
python from outputting one of those funny
阻止python输出那些
rank 1 arraies where the dimensions
秩为1的数组
was you n comma so by having keep
这个数组的维度是(n,)
them equals True this ensures that
如果让这个参数等于True
Python outputs for db[2] a vector that is
可以确保Python输出的db[2]是一个
um n by one technically this will be
(n,1)维的向量
I guess n[2] by one in this case is
严格的说是(n[2],1)维
just a one by one number so maybe it
这个例子中是一个1*1的数字
doesn't matter but later on we'll see
看起来并不重要
what it really matters so so far what
我们稍后会看到他真正重要的原因
we've done is very similar to logistic
我们刚才做的非常像logistic回归
regression but now as you compute
接下来继续
continue to run back propagation you
进行反向传播的计算
would compute this dz[2] times g[1] prime
你需要计算dz[2]*g[1]'(z[1])
of Z1 so this quantity g[1] prime is the
g[1]'表示隐含层
derivative of whatever was the
activation function you use for the
的激活函数的导数
hidden layer and for the output layer I
对于输出层 我假定你
assume that you're doing binary
使用sigmoid函数
classification with the sigmoid function
做二分类
so that's already baked into that
sigmoid函数的导数
formula for dz[2] and this times is a
已经在dz[2]中计算了
element-wise product so this
这里的乘法是矩阵对应元素直接相乘
there's going to be an N 1 by M matrix
这个的计算结果是(n1,m)维的矩阵
and this here this element wise
这里是对所有元素
derivative thing is also going to be an
进行求导 最终的结果也是
n[1] by m matrix and so this times there
(n[1],m)的矩阵 因此 这里的乘法
is an element-wise product of two
是对两个矩阵的每一个对应元素相乘
matrices then finally DW 1 is equal to
dw[1]等于这个
that and db1 is equal to this np.sum
db1=np.sum(dz[1],axis=1,keepdims=True)
dz[1] axis equals 1 keepdims
equals true so whereas
db1=np.sum(dz[1],axis=1,keepdims=True)
previously the keepdims maybe
之前keepdims看起来没什么用
matter less if n2 is equal to 1 so
如果n2=1
it's just a one by one thing it's just a real
结果仅是一个数字
number here db1 will be a n1 by 1
这里 db1是一个(n1,1)的向量
vector and so you want Python you want
你希望np.sum输出
np.sum output something of this
一个这样的维度
dimension rather than a funny rank one
而不是一个秩1数组
array of that dimension which could end
那样会使你之后的计算
up messing up some of your later
变得麻烦
calculations the other way would be to
另一种方式就是
not have to keep them parameters but to
不把这个参数设置为True
explicitly call you know a reshape to reshape
而是调用reshape
the output of NP dot sum into this
把np.sum的输出变成
dimension which you would like DB to have
你想要的维度
so that was forward propagation em I gives
我给了4个公式用于
four equations and back propagation and I
前向传播 给出了6个公式用于
gives six equations I know I just wrote
反向传播 我目前仅仅是把这些公式
down these equations but in the next
写了出来 下个视频中
optional video let's go over some
我们来看看这6个用于
intuitions for how the six equations for
反向传播的公式
the back propagation algorithm were
是如何推导出来的
derived please feel free to watch that
你看不看下个视频都是可以的
or not but either way if you implement
但是不管怎样 如果你去实现这些
these algorithms you will have a correct
算法 你已经知道了实现
implementation of forward propagate and back propagate
前向传播和反向传播的正确公式
and you'll be able to compute the
你能够计算
derivatives you need in order to apply
用于梯度下降的导数
gradient descent to learn the parameters
学习出神经网络的参数
of your neural network it is possible to
implement the algorithm and get it to work
不深入理解微积分去
without deeply understanding the
实现神经网络是可行的
calculus a lot of successful deep learning
许多成功的深度学习从业者
practitioners do so but if you
都不是很了解微积分
want you can also watch the next video
你也可以看下一个视频
just to get a bit more intuition about
了解这些公式
the derivation of these um these equations
是如何推导的